<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Import PhD</title><link href="http://importphd.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://importphd.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://importphd.com/</id><updated>2018-07-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Kernel panic: Fatal Exception</title><link href="http://importphd.com/kernel-panic-fatal-exception.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Kail</name></author><id>tag:importphd.com,2018-07-23:/kernel-panic-fatal-exception.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in the first blog post, there are a few reason in which I
started to write this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Practice&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a good opportunity for practice in writing. Yes, I know its a blog and not papers or publications.
Its still writing, and sometimes it may become …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in the first blog post, there are a few reason in which I
started to write this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Practice&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a good opportunity for practice in writing. Yes, I know its a blog and not papers or publications.
Its still writing, and sometimes it may become technical.  That is my hope at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Focus&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past I have tried several times to start a blog of some sort.  I remember I attempted one during
graduage school and wrote briefly about a conference I attended. I quickly forgot about it. That
was until I interviewed at my current job and one of the interviewers had apparently google searched me
and found the blog and its single post.  Still not sure where that page is now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have a focus for the next few years I feel inclined to write something with meaning.  I hope
that this will prove fruitful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fear&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the main catalyst of this blog started a few weeks ago when I had a small panic
attach while at work.  I was in contact with my advisor to discuss my scheduling for
my first semester. I took a few minutes to look around at what people were saying about
going back to get a PhD while also working full-time.  Here's some of the things I found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some not so encouring finds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-do-PhD-while-working"&gt;Is it possible to do a Phd while working&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some a little more encouraging&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://academia.stackexchange.com/questions/8747/is-it-possible-to-work-full-time-and-complete-a-phd"&gt;Is it possible to work full time and complete a phd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And some that show others doing the same thing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://womenincoastal.org/youre-doing-a-phd-part-time-while-working-full-time-are-you-insane/"&gt;Are you insane?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading a few of these I began to question my decision to do this.  It wasn't too late. I could
step back and let the professors know that I wasn't willing to commit and couldn't do it.  That's not what I
did though.  A serious panic started to seep into my mind and I found myself frozen
at my desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="no body panic" src="http://importphd.com/images/sheldon-hyperventilate.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes sitting there, I stepped back, texted my wife what I was feeling, and told myself that its been done by others.
I coasted through most of college, even my Masters, without doing close to 100%. What would happen if I actually
focused on what I was doing. It also helps that I have lots of support, both from my family and also from work.
I am lucky that I have a flexible job with good working hours and management that is in full support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now how did that lead to a blog?  Well, one of the many articles I read about keeping up your motivation
during a PhD program suggested writing a blog. After a bit of thinking, I figured that was a good idea.
Especially if I am to make it through the &lt;a href="http://juliopeironcely.com/archives/5-phases-of-phd-motivation-explained-the-roller-coaster-curve.html"&gt;Crisis of Meaning&lt;/a&gt;
in the next several years.  Plus, it holds me accountable and by sharing my experience will help others who are
also working full time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I have some goals now for my PhD. Some are my minimum expectations and some are moonshot goals. I am focused and ready
to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~ Andrew&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="health"></category></entry><entry><title>ModuleNotFoundError: No module named 'phd'</title><link href="http://importphd.com/modulenotfounderror-no-module-named-phd.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Andrew Kail</name></author><id>tag:importphd.com,2018-07-15:/modulenotfounderror-no-module-named-phd.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ok, after almost 5 years working and developing Python Codes. Its
time for a phd.  Easy right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;phd&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Traceback&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;most&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;recent&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;call&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;last&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="n"&gt;File&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;lt;stdin&amp;gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;line&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;module&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;ModuleNotFoundError&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;No&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;module&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;named&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;phd&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Wait....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center inline-image" &gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://giphy.com/embed/2fs2I4ujlBf20" width="480" height="270" frameBorder="0" class="giphy-embed" allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I forget... it doesn't work like &lt;code&gt;import antigravity&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you've somehow wandered over to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ok, after almost 5 years working and developing Python Codes. Its
time for a phd.  Easy right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;phd&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Traceback&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;most&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;recent&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;call&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;last&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="n"&gt;File&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;lt;stdin&amp;gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;line&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;module&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;ModuleNotFoundError&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;No&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;module&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;named&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;phd&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Wait....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center inline-image" &gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://giphy.com/embed/2fs2I4ujlBf20" width="480" height="270" frameBorder="0" class="giphy-embed" allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I forget... it doesn't work like &lt;code&gt;import antigravity&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you've somehow wandered over to
this blog and I would like to personally welcome you here.  This is going to be
a documentation of my journey towards a PhD while also working a full time job. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So who am I? My name is Andrew Kail and I graduated from the University of Tennessee in 2011 and 2013 with a Bachelor and Masters degree
in Aerospace engineering.  Currently I'm a Senior Scientist at Savannah River National 
Laboratory in South Carolina where I am a jack of all trades in the computing group, but mostly
"They Pythong Guy".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm starting a PhD after having worked at a National Lab for
5 years.  Why?  I keep asking myself that same question everytime I think about the start
of classes in a few weeks.  Its been on my mind for a while now and was a little bit when I was finishing
up my Masters.  At the time I was definitely not ready to continue my education from a maturity
and work ethic standpoint, and thankfully my advisor made sure I knew that. I also had no idea what
degree I would like to pursue or what I was even doing with my career really.  I was an Aerospace Engineer who
realized he was far more interested in programming and computing than building rockets and planes. Given a few years
and self reflection I started to consider the idea more and more (especially when I realized I could get it payed for by
work).  I had a few roadblocks though, I liked my job, couldn't find a program nearby in semi-rural South Carolina, and I just
didn't like the idea of doing a CompSci degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things took a turn in December when I discovered the &lt;a href="https://ualr.edu/online/programs/cis/"&gt;Information Science&lt;/a&gt; program 
at the University of Arkansas Little Rock.  It piqued my interest. It covered a lot of the topics I was interested in
such as data science, machine learning, information system architecture and visualization. It also allows me to work remotely
and the courses are held at reasonable hours so I could continue to work full time.
I was accepted into the program about a month ago and have been working to get everything taken care of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, why the blog? I'll cover the why in more detail in another post so come back for more! As for what you can expect,
here are some of the things I will be trying to cover: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall Progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total cost of my PhD process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fun content to keep my spirits up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Useful links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading Recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hopefully links and announcements on publications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and General updates and frustrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read this and stick around I really appreciate and I hope we all can get something out of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~ Andrew&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>